// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Software project manager is engaged with software management activities. He is responsible for",
    answer: "All mentioned above",
    options: ["Project planning", "Monitoring the progress", "Communication among stakeholders", "All mentioned above"],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a software project",
    answer: "Routine tasks are involved",
    options: [ "Project is complex and large" ,"Routine tasks are involved","Project has a predetermined time span" ,"Project is carried out for others wareproject"],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Choose the correct order of activities covered by software project management ",
    answer: "Feasibility, Planning, Design and Execution",
    options: ["Planning, Analysis, Feasibility and Execution", "Requirement elicitation, Analysis, Planning and Execution", "Feasibility, Planning, Design and Execution", "Execution, Planning, Feasibility and Design"],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Who identified the characteristics to differentiate between s/w projects and other type of projects?",
    answer: "Fred brooks",
    options: ["Fred brooks", "Bob Hughes", "Mike Cotrell", "None of the above"
      ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which is the next step after PFD –Product Flow Diagram?",
    answer: "Ideal activity network",
    options: ["Product Breakdown Structure", "Work breakdown structure", "Ideal activity network", "None of the above"
      ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What should be done by the project manager to ensure that all work in the project is included?",
    answer: "Create a WBS",
    options: ["Create a contingency plan", "Create a risk management plan", "Create a WBS", "Create a scope statement" 
     ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Technique used to frame Objectives and Sub Objectives of a Project",
    answer: "SMART – Specific Measurable Achievable Relevant Time constrained",
    options: ["PBS –Product Breakdown Structure",
       "PFD – Product Flow Diagram",
      "SMART – Specific Measurable Achievable Relevant Time constrained",
      "SMART – Special Measurable Accepted Real-time Task"
     ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What should a project manager do or follow to ensure clear boundaries for project completion?",
    answer: "Completing a scope statement",
    options: ["Scope verification",
      "Completing a scope statement",
      "scope definition",
      "Risk management plan"
      ],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What does the acronym SMART stand for?",
    answer: "Specific, measurable, achievable, relevant, time constrained",
    options: ["Suitable, measurable, actionable, relevant, time constrained",
      "Specific, measurable, actionable, resourced, time constrained",
      "Standardised, measurable, achievable, relevant, time constrained",
      "Specific, measurable, achievable, relevant, time constrained"
      ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which one of the following is an appropriate sequence of steps in project planning?"    ,
    answer: "Develop product breakdown structure, develop activity network, estimate effort and allocate resource",
    options: ["Develop product breakdown structure, develop activity network, estimate effort and allocate resource",
      "Develop activity network, develop product breakdown structure, estimate effort and allocate resource",
      "Develop product breakdown structure, estimate effort, develop activity network and allocate resource",
      "Allocate resource, develop product breakdown structure, develop activity network and estimate effort"
      ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Actor-Technology – Structure – Task is factors of which of the following",
    answer: "Socio technical Model of risk",
    options: ["Project Plan",
    "Corrective Action",
    "Scope statement",
    "Socio technical Model of risk"
   ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "_________ is the difference between the total costs and the total income over the life of the project.",
    answer: "Net profit",
    options: ["Payback period",
      "Net present value",
      "Net profit",
      "Internal rate of return"
      ],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "When the IRR is equal to the discount rate, what can be said about the NPV?",
    answer: "It would be equal to zero",
    options: [ "It would be positive",
      "It would be equal to zero",
      "It would be negative",
      "It cannot be determined without knowing the exact discount rate"],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "_________ merges several projects.",
    answer: "Strategic programes",
    options: ["Strategic programes",
    "Business cycle programmes",
    "Project manager",
    "Benefits management"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "_________ manages one project at a time.",
    answer: "Project manager",
    options: ["Strategic programes",
      "Business cycle programes",
      "Project manager",
      "Benefits management"
      ],
  },
];
